ADAMA SALL

Norwich, 14 Imperial House Rose-Lane NR1 1BZ
Phone: 07487359264 | Email: adamal.sall@gmail.com
LinkedIn: Write out Link | GitHub: https://github.com/Kaiyfa | Portfolio: https://kaiyfa.github.io/Adama-portfolio/

SUMMARY

front-end web developer with an electromechanics background (over 5 years of experience) tackling complex bugs with a rational problem-solving approach. graduated from the Edex Trilogy Bootcamp and developed skills in JavaScript, CSS, React.js, Bootstrap, jQuery, and responsive web design. having a thirst for lifelong learning, collaboration, and problem solving, and being equally enthusiastic about developing applications that help ordinary people make their lives easier. In order to give the best user experience possible, each project should strive to be the best at engaging the audience. I am excited to use my abilities in the future as part of a fast-paced, quality-driven team to create better web experiences. I'm excited to put my precise attention to detail and technical talents to work for a company that values growth, learning, and making a major contribution.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools: Express, React, Node, Handlebars, Query, Bootstrap, Server-side APIs, AJAX, and JSON

Languages: JavaScript ES6, CSS, HTML5, Typescript

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL

PROJECTS

PASSWORD GENERATOR: HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/KAIYFA/PASSWORD-GENERATOR HTTPS://KAIYFA.GITHUB.IO/PASSWORD-GENERATOR/

Summary: An employee can generate a random password based on criteria they've selected.

Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, GoogleFonts, wireframing

Role: Sole author

WEB QUIZ APPLICATION: HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/KAIYFA/WEB_APIS-QUIZ HTTPS://KAIYFA.GITHUB.IO/WEB_APIS-QUIZ/

Summary: A timed, multiple-choice coding quiz that keeps track of high scores and quiz takers' initials

Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs

Role: Sole author

PLANNER APPLICATION: HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/KAIYFA/JQUERY-PLANNER-APP | HTTPS://KAIYFA.GITHUB.IO/JQUERY-PLANNER-APP |

Summary: An employee can generate a random password based on criteria they've selected.

Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, GoogleFonts, wireframing

Role: Sole author

EXPERIENCE

Electromechanical Technician/Full time Employee Sabodala Gold Operations

Jun. 2019 – Nov. 2020 Kedougou, Senegal

The main duty was troubleshooting breakdowns and performing preventive maintenance. **Key Accomplishments**:

- Analyzed quality issues concerning a loader WA900 in a rational and methodical manner, saving the firm money USD \$225,000.
- Led a group of 4 people for four weeks in a row, offering excellent levels of equipment availability (97.8%) to our internal client while sticking to the Mean Time Between Failures, resulting in a strong production bonus for all colleagues the following month.
- Held a safety meeting for our department presentation for four weeks in a row (every morning before beginning activities) due to my ease of public speaking and English proficiency.
- Received a 5,000 CFA safety prize for holding and conducting a housekeeping operation in an abandoned property.

Senior Electromechanical Technician/Full-Time Employee, Soeco/Poncet April 2017-May 2019

Thiès, Sénégal

I supervised, maintained, and ran a crushing unit, including machine operator maintenance.

Key Accomplishments:

- Installation of a crusher unit from the ground up in two months.
- Improved and enlarged a maintenance notebook in Microsoft Excel to keep track of records
- launched a new unit of two Lokotrack LT106 and LT200 HP mobile crushers that improved production from 90–1200 tons per hour to 80–2500 tons per hour.
- Achieved annual goal targets in six months with both production quality and unit availability allowing Soeco to open another pit and invest in new machinery and projects.
- Controlling the supply chain to avoid fuel, spare parts, and oil shortages

EDUCATION

Front-End web Development Certificate - Edx Trilogy Education Services-2022-2023

 A 16-week intensive program focused on developing technical programming abilities in HTML5, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js, and ReactJS.

Advanced Technician's Certificate in Heavy Equipment Maintenance - Senegal-Japan Training Center Dakar, Senegal 2014 - 2016

Baccalaureate (High school diploma) in Mechanical Manufacturing - Technical School Maurice Delafosse Dakar, Senegal 2009 - 2010

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Technology:

- Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- Google slide, drive and doc

Languages:

English: Intermediate level grade 7.5 on IELTS

French: Fluent

References are available on request.